Welcome to our training start selling subscription boxes.
Customers use the Amazon store every day to purchase products they're familiar with.
But many also use the selection available through Amazon to discover new products, brands and services.
If you're a seller looking to reach more customers, you can help them explore in the Amazon store
by selling subscription boxes.
A subscription box is a curated collection of products in a single category that's sent to a customer
on a recurring basis.
Each box contains a different set of products assembled by the seller.
Customers subscribe to a subscription box service and pay a regular amount per cycle so they can
keep discovering new items.
Subscription boxes come in a variety of categories, including beauty, food and drink, pets, toys
and kids and t-shirts.
They can be created with variations, meaning different versions of the same subscription box can
be sent to different customers.
Sellers who sell subscription boxes can include their own
branded products or items they're reselling from other brands.
They can also include products that are already listed in the Amazon store or new products that
customers can only receive by subscribing to their subscription box.
You can apply anytime to sell subscription boxes in the Amazon store.
Visit sell.
amazon.
com and hover over the start drop-down menu.
Then click Amazon Selling Programs.
On the Programs page, scroll down, find the Sell Subscription Boxes tile, and click Learn More.
Then click the apply now button on the next page to access the application.
We'll respond to your application via email within 7 to 10 business days.
If you're approved, you'll then need to set up your seller central account for subscription box
sales and fill out a subscription box listing template.
Let's review seller central account setup first.
Start by creating a professional selling account if you don't have one already.
Visit sell.
amazon.
com.
Click the sign up button and follow the prompts.
Next, complete all state-specific tax settings in Seller Central if you haven't done so already.
Sign in to Seller Central, click the gear icon and then click tax settings.
Follow the prompts to complete the process.
Finally, create a subscription box specific shipping template in Seller Central.
Click the gear icon, then shipping settings, and then the create new shipping template button.
On the next page, enter a shipping template name.
Then, under domestic shipping, select standard shipping as your sole shipping method.
Make sure you don't accidentally select shipping region automation, which doesn't apply to subscription
boxes.
Then, select the 48 contiguous US states, Hawaii, Alaska, and Puerto Rico, and Guam as your regions.
These are the only regions where Amazon subscription boxes can be shipped.
Make sure you're able to send boxes to each location directly.
After selecting regions, enter a shipping fee of $0 for each one.
When you've completed all entries for your shipping template, click the save button.
On the next page, take a screenshot of your full template and copy and save the string of alphanumeric
characters
between the number sign and slash success in the URL.
You'll need this screenshot and alphanumeric string later.
Once you have a professional selling account with the right tax settings and shipping template,
you're ready to fill out a listing template for your subscription boxes.
You can download the template using the link included in the email you received from the subscription
box team.
When you open the template, start by reviewing the instructions, examples, data definitions,
and valid values sheets for information and guidance.
Then, add your subscription box information to the template sheet.
Let's review entries on the template sheet specific to subscription boxes.
If you'd like more information about additional required entries,
you can review our other modules in Seller University
about creating listings and product variations in bulk.
The first entry you'll add to the template sheet will be for product type.
For each row, make sure subscription box is selected.
Next, in the byline column, enter the brand name of your subscription box service.
If you need to add variation information to the template,
keep in mind that only three variations or fewer can be included in a subscription box file upload.
If you want your subscription box to come in more than three variations,
you can make entries in additional rows.
But keep in mind that you'll need to send your completed listing template back to the subscription
box team
for manual processing rather than trying to upload it yourself in Seller Central.
When you add offer information to the listing template, start by choosing whether you want to send
your subscription boxes
to customers every one, two, or three months.
You can also choose to offer an introductory price if you want customers to receive their first
box at a discount.
Next, when entering fulfillment information, select anniversary shipping as your shipping type,
if for each cycle you want to send a box to each customer within seven business days of the specific
date they started their subscription.
Or select calendar-based shipping to indicate that you'll send subscription boxes to all customers
within seven business days
of the same date in each cycle.
Remember that if you select anniversary shipping, you'll receive and fulfill orders on a rolling
basis.
But if you select calendar-based shipping, you'll receive and fulfill all orders simultaneously
once per cycle.
After selecting your shipping type, enter the string of alphanumeric characters you saved from your
shipping template URL
in the shipping template ID column.
Then, if you selected calendar-based shipping, provide a cutoff day of the month that will be used
for each subscription box cycle
as well as the first cutoff date for your service.
You'll also need to enter a fulfillment day of the month and first fulfillment date if you selected
calendar-based shipping.
Base both on your entries from the two previous columns.
Finally, to complete your listing template, open the shipping template sheet
and insert the screenshot you took of your shipping template in Seller Central.
After completing your template, you can upload it to the same page in Seller Central where you downloaded
a blank copy.
Or, to share a listing template that includes more than three variations,
reply to the email you received from the subscription box team.
You can also reply to the subscription box team if you have questions
or want to explore options like Customize and Subscribe,
which allows customers to request certain types of products in their subscription boxes.
We'll notify you when we've listed your subscription box and launched your service in the Amazon
Store.
This concludes our training.
Thank you and happy selling in the Amazon Store!